leeds.gov.uk 2005-12-31

# Leeds City Council - Internet privacy statement

  |  | 

Online services|Website guide and policies| 

**General**   
The privacy of our customers and citizens has always been of great importance to the Council. The Council has a long history of protecting your privacy, and our concern for your privacy is no different in the electronic age, or with the advent of e-government.

  * You do not have to give us any personal data, or private information about yourself, to visit our site.
  * If you visit our site just to read or download information, we will collect and store only the following information (web access logs) about your visit. Most local authorities, and companies maintain these logs as a function of operating websites. These logs do not contain any personal data or private information, and we do not make any attempt to link the traffic information in the logs, with the individuals who actually visit our site.
  * The name of the domain from which you access the Internet, and the Internet Protocol (IP) address or host name, which may or may not identify a specific computer.
  * The date and time you access our site.
  * The pages you visit.
  * The Internet address of any website from which you linked directly to our site.
  * We will collect personal data or private information only if this is provided specifically and knowingly by you, using an online form, or by sending us email.
  * Personal data or private information which you provide will be used only for such purposes as are described at the point of collection, or for purposes which are legally permitted.
  * We will only share your personal data or private information with outside parties in ways that are permitted by this Statement, or if we are required to do so by law, or to comply with a court order.
  * Web access logs may be used to prevent security breaches, and to ensure the integrity of the data on our servers. The logs are deleted periodically. When you send us an email, using the form on our site, we retain a log of the time each message is received by the server, the source and destination address of each message, the time each message is forwarded, and the delivery status of each message. Again, these logs are deleted periodically.

**Site Management**   
For site management, information from web access and email logs is collected for statistical purposes. Summary statistics are created, which are used for such purposes as assessing the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, what information on our site is of most and least interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas.

**Site Security**   
For site security purposes, the Council arranges for network traffic to be monitored, to investigate or detect unauthorised uses, such as attempts to upload or change information, or attacks on services, or other attacks intended to cause damage. This means that when you send us an email, (whether you use the form on our site or otherwise), we could intercept it, or it could be intercepted on our behalf.

**Links**   
Our site contains links to and from other web sites. Please note that these web sites’ may deal with privacy differently, and the Council will have no responsibility or liability for the privacy practices, or the content of any linked site. The Council does not necessarily endorse or support the services or business, of those organisations to or from which this site is linked. The Council cannot guarantee that these links will work all of the time, and has no control over the availability of the linked pages. If you decide to access third party sites linked to this site, you do so at your own risk, and the Council has no right to anyone else’s intellectual property on those sites. If you want to link to pages on our site, you need to get our permission first. Please see the contact details on this page.

**"Cookies"**   
A cookie file can contain certain information such as a user ID, that a web site can use to track the pages you have visited. We do not use cookies at present. If we decide to use cookies in the future, we will include full details in this Internet Privacy Statement, and cookies will not be associated with any personal data or private information.

**Security**   
Please note that sending an email, or submitting information via an online form, cannot be made totally secure. Whilst we strive to protect your personal data and private information, the Council cannot ensure the security of any information in an email or an online form, whilst this is being transmitted to us.

**Third Party Service Provider**   
The Council may have contracts with third parties, to help provide online services. If we do, we will make sure that

  * they are provided only with the information which they need to carry out the service
  * they agree not to use the information received from the Council, for any purpose other than that specified by the Council, and
  * they have proper systems in place to protect personal data and private information.

**Copyright**

  * All intellectual property rights are reserved. Generally, the reproduction or transmission, in any form or by any means, or the storing in any retrieval system of any nature, of any text, graphics, images, film or sound files, code, design or logo is forbidden without the Council’s written permission. Our copyright, and other intellectual property rights, are protected by UK laws, and by international treaties.
  * However, any text can be downloaded by our customers and citizens free of charge, to file or printer without our permission. This is subject to the material being reproduced accurately, and not being re-used or re-published in any way. This permission does not extend to any material on our site, which belongs to someone else, for example where it is identified as being the copyright of someone else.

**Names etc.**   
The name "Leeds City Council," and the historic names of the Council, and the Council’s common seal are protected by Royal Charters. The Council’s Coat of Arms is protected by letters patent. None of these must be used without the Council’s prior written permission.

**Virus Protection**   
We make every effort to check and test the material on our site. However, it is always wise to run an anti-virus program on all material downloaded from the Internet. The Council cannot accept any responsibility or liability for any loss, disruption or damage to your data or to your computer system, which may occur as a result of using material from our site.

**Disclaimer**   
Whilst we use all reasonable endeavours to ensure that the material on our site is accurate and up to date, the Council cannot accept any responsibility or liability for any loss, or claim arising directly or indirectly from any error or inaccuracy in any of the material on this web site.

**Contact**   
Requests to use any material protected by copyright, or other intellectual property rights, and requests to link to pages on our site, should be made to the webmaster

Requests to use the name, historic names, common seal, or Coat of Arms should be made to the Lord Mayor’s Secretary, Civic Hall, Leeds LS1 1UR.

If you would like to contact us about this Internet Privacy Statement, or if you think any of the information on our site is wrong, or inaccurate, please email us.

**Information Commissioner's Office**   
The Information Commissioner enforces and oversees the Data Protection Act 1998 (DPA) and the Freedom of Information Act 2000 (FOI) .

The Commissioner is a UK independent supervisory authority reporting directly to the UK Parliament and has an international role as well as a national one.
